# ROMINA CARABA-THAMPI, MSc.

**Machine Learning Engineer** 

+1 519 591 9012 | LinkedIn | Github

Proficiencies: Python (TensorFlow, keras, matplotlib, pandas), Jupyter, R. SOL, Matlab, Tableau, Microsoft Office, LaTeX, AWS, git, bash, Linux, Javascript

romina.caraba@gmail.com | https://rominacarabathampi.ca/ Enthusiastic Machine Learning Engineer with 4 years of experience with Python. Clear understanding of machine learning models and TensorFlow. Motivated to learn, grow and excel in the tech industry.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

### **Machine Learning Engineer**

Mar 2020 – present

**NOVACENE AI** 

Remote

- Implemented and evaluated artificial intelligence and machine learning algorithm for the private sector.
- Analysed the Canadian COVID-19 data and built a predictive model for total number of cases in June.

**Robotics and Mathematics Teacher** 

Sep 2019 – March 2020

Crania Schools

Waterloo

Taught students how to understand and solve K-12 math problems. Documented and communicated student progress on course goals to identify areas of improvement.

## **Code Mentor and Technical Translator**

Feb - Jul 2019

Codeberry

Remote

Monitored and managed student progress to identify areas of improvement for HTML, CSS and Javascript. Collaborated in remote teams to support student education by reviewing translation of technical terms to Romanian.

## **EDUCATION**

**Brainstation** 

Jun - Sep 2019

Toronto

Data Science Diploma

Capstone Project: Automated cancer detection from images of lymph node sections. Built a Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) using Python's TensorFlow library.

#### **BIOTEC Technical University of Dresden**

2016 - 2018

Master of Science in Nanobiophysics

Dresden, Germany

- Graduate Research Thesis: Consolidated team's belief that interaction fingerprints provide more accurate results in the drug research industry. Used SQL, Python's pandas and numpy, and R to create interactive Principal Component Analysis (PCA) maps.
- **Teaching Assistant for Applied Bioinformatics:** Instructed students on using Python in Bioinformatics, Redesigned assignments to bolster students' understanding of tricky Bioinformatics concepts.

## West University of Timisoara

2012 - 2015

Bachelor of Science in Nanobiophysics

Timisoara, Romania

- **Undergraduate Research Thesis**: Implemented the heat equation in Mathcad to simulate the radiation effect on various organs in the human body.
- **Teaching Assistant for Introduction to C Programming**: Conducted a laboratory section with coding in C for Physics Major.
- **Undergraduate Research Assistant:** Developed a numerical simulation of crystal growth in space under zerogravity conditions using CrysVUn software.

## **PROJECTS**

- Covid-19 Canada Prediction: Analyzed Canadian COVID-19 case data and built a predictive model in Python to predict possible numbers of active cases for the month of June.
- Space App Challenge Waterloo: Analyzed the data from the CSA Space App Challenge regarding Neutron radiation on the International Space Station and across Canada.
- Automating Cancer Detection: Machine Learning project for automating detection of cancerous tissue from lymph nodes sections. Open data from Patch Camelyon Challenge.
- Toronto Crime Analysis: Exploratory Data Analysis of crimes in GTA from 2014 2018. Contains data cleaning and analysis of trends over time.
- Open Source Contribution: Translating the Ubuntu package dock. Translating the Romanian Locale for Ubuntu Women. Translating Legesher Ubuntu package to Romanian.